Jon Hanks



jonhanks@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/jonhanks



5129259974



https://github.com/hanks42

Summary

Technical engineering leader with 15+ years experience in software development and technology businesses. Familiar with all aspects of both the software development lifecycle and the product development lifecycle. With an educational background in entrepreneurship and experience in startups I bring a customer focused mentality to the software development process that seeks to align business goals and objectives with technical excellence. I have extensive experience in software architecture, developing web applications and microservices, and leading teams to create great solutions that push the business forward.

Experience

Staff Software Engineer

Indeed.com

2018 - Present (4 years 4 months +)

Leading a team of 4 software engineers with the goal of providing a best in class compliance experience during our software development lifecycle (SDLC). We provide tools to assist with security, accessibility, test automation, and more.

Play an active role in the ongoing enhancements to the Indeed standard software development lifecycle. Consult with many teams within Indeed engineering on their system architecture to produce enhanced solutions and establish best practices.

Establish and promote internal best practices around DevOps principles such as: continuous integration, continuous deployment, use of microservices, infrastructure as code, monitoring, test automation and verification.

Architect and play an active role in the software development for systems that make use of various industry standard and innovative components including: AWS, Docker, Terraform, Kubernetes

Senior Software Engineer

Indeed.com

2014 - 2018 (5 years)

Developed and architected many of the internal tools, applications, and systems for the growing number of developers at Indeed, as an early member of Indeed's delivery engineering group (DEG). This empowered developers to optimize their work done during the software development lifecycle (SDLC). Also performed extensive back-end web development work to create applications and microservices that were integrated into the SDLC.

Led, designed, and developed Docker and Python based solutions to speed up developer velocity during the SDLC for developers using both Linux and Mac environments. These tools are still in use and have supported a 10x growth in Indeed's engineering size.

Initiated and led the global migration of hundreds of Indeed's microservices from Python version 2 to 3.

Developed supporting libraries and frameworks to champion the use of Python from a niche rarely used language at Indeed to the language of the largest amount newly created code at Indeed.

Provided mentorship to junior and mid-level engineers on software design and development best practices.

Prepify CTO and Co-Founder

Prepify

2014 - 2014 (1 year)

Led a team of 3 technical members at this seed-stage startup. Oversaw development of our web based SAT learning platform for high school students. Developed the platform using Python, Django, and Rackspace Open Cloud. Led adoption of standard management techniques including Kanban, Agile methodologies, and technical code reviews.

Principal

Texas Venture Labs

2013 - 2013 (1 year)

Led a team of students working with startup businesses Equipboard and Primizie Snacks to meet their marketing and customer acquisition goals.

Technical Intern - Product Management Group

Adlucent

2013 - 2013 (1 year)

Designed a day parting system for Google Adwords ad buys that resulted in a 22% increase in ROI. Developed a day parting optimization system in Python that could make recommendations based on vast historical data. MBA Internship.

Research Assistant

University of Texas

2013 - 2013 (1 year)

Built Python based models of meeting activity from over 70 thousand politician communication logs to explore patterns and groupings of participants to these communications.

Associate

Texas Venture Labs

2013 - 2013 (1 year)

Worked with startups Infinite IO and Carnegie Design Systems to improve their business plans and investor relations.

Organizer

3 Day Startup

2013 - 2013 (1 year)

Mentored participants on the idea generation and market validation stages of their startups.

Technical Marketing Director and Founder

Mesozoic Media, LLC

2007 - 2012 (6 years)

Developed product marketing software to manage multiple websites that displayed millions of products. Consulted with game companies on how to use data to drive improvements to their KPIs.

Technical Marketing Consultant

Hellfire Games

2011 - 2011 (1 year)

Designed and developed a web based analytics dashboard for the game Novus Prime. Launched a social media campaign doubling the Facebook following. Grew a mailing list from 0 to over 20,000 subscribers.

Marketing Consultant

Playtechtonics 2007 - 2009 (3 years)

Software Engineer

Pixel Mine Games 2007 - 2007 (1 year)

Software Engineer

Super Happy Fun Fun 2005 - 2006 (2 years)

Game Programmer

Everi Holdings Inc.

Oct 2004 - Dec 2005 (1 year 3 months)

Education

The University of Texas at Austin

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), MBA

♥ Virginia Tech

B.S., Mathematics

Focusing on Applied Discrete Mathematics

Virginia Tech

B.S., Computer Science

Computer Science GPA 3.93/4 - Overall GPA 3.73/4

Skills

Python • Entrepreneurship • Software Development Li • Linux • System Architecture • Software

Design • Microservices • Terraform • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Test Automation

Honors & Awards



Phi Beta Kappa - Virginia Tech

https://www.pbk.org/About

Inducted at undergraduate graduation to America's most prestigious academic honor society. Honors the best and brightest liberal arts and sciences undergraduates from 290 top schools across the nation through a highly selective, merit-based invitation process.

Angelhack Austin 2013 Winner

Member of team PeerLearn the winner of the AngelHack hackathon in Austin, June 2013. Developed the collaborative online whiteboard aspect of the PearLearn product.